

Sergei Kharin

Researcher, Agricultural Economics

- November 3, 1979
- 27A Timiryazeva str. APT 189 Voronezh, Russia 394087
- +7 473 253 7290
- https://sergeikharin.github.io/html-repo/
- @ kharins03@gmail.com
- Russian

Social Network –

ResearchGate Link

Facebook Link

Languages

Russian

English

Slovak

Digital Skills

Programming languages
(Python and R program)

Gretl

■ Microsoft Office■ ● ● ● ●■ Zoom, MS Teams■ ● ● ●

HTML/CSS

Academic ID

- Google Scholar Link
- E Elsevier Scopus Link
- Publons Link
- ORCID Link

Education and Training

Postdoctoral Training

2013 – 2023 **Research Stay, EU** Estonia, Sweden, Germany, Slovakia Spending up to 6 months abroad doing research in the field of price

transmission analysis along food supply chains

2013 – 2015 Summer School on Macroeconomics New Economic School (Russia, Moscow)

In-depth studies on the intermediate, advanced and global macroeconomics

2013 – 2013 Cambridge English Exams

Cambridge ESOL Entry Level Certificate in ESOL International (Coun-

cil of Europe Level B1 in English)

Program for

2008 – 2008 **professional** Institute of professional accountants of Russia(IPAR)

accountants

Advanced training programme for professional accountants

Education

PhD Studies, Ph.D.(The first

2002 – 2005 academic degree "Candidate of Voronezh State Agricultural University

Economic Sciences" in Russia)Field of study: Agricultural Economics

Ph.D.Dissertation Voronezh State Agricultural University

Prices, pricing and regulation in agricultural sector

1997 – 2002 Master Studies, M.Sc. in Voronezh State Agricultural University

EconomicsField of study: Agricultural Economics

Master Theses Voronezh State Agricultural University

Mechanism of the circulating capital control in agricultural enter-

prises and it's improvement ways

Working Experience

2022 – 2024 **Researcher** IER, Slovak Academy of Sciences

Doing Research, giving speech with presentations, writing papers under the EU project No. 09I03-03-V01-00054"Next Generation

EU through the Recovery and Resilience Plan for Slovakia"

2017 – 2022 Senior Voronezh State University of Forestry and Technologies (VSUFT)

Executive secretary at the Editorial Board of the journal "Forestry Engineering Journal"; research activity, publishing papers in scientific journals, indexed by the international databases, applying for

various scholarships and grants; part-time teaching

2005 – 2017 Lecturer, Assistant Professor VSUFT

Mobility activity within Erasmus Mundus and DAAD programs; teaching bachelors; doing research within the framework of the Chair research issue "Problems of Russian economy modernisation under

current conditions"

2006 – 2010 Chief Accountant LLC "Business-Center "Etazhi"

Responsible for accounting policy and tax reports

Awards

2020 – 2021 Expansion|research grant

Grant for review article publication funded by Russian Foundation

for Basic Research (RFBR) | project №20-110-50002

2020 – 2020 DAAD scholarship

Mobility grant within German Exchange Academic Service (DAAD) programme: Germany, Giessen, Justus Liebig University in Giessen

| research 3-month stay 2019 – 2020 | **Research grant**

Grant was funded by the Academician Nikolai Fedorenko International Scientific Foundation of Economic Research (ISFER) project

№ 2019-124. 2018 – 2018 Immanuel Kant | research programme

Mobility grant within joint DAAD and the Russian Ministry of Science and Higher Education programme №26.12725.2018/12.2: Germany, Giessen, Justus Liebig University in Giessen | research 3-

month stay

Sergei Kharin

Researcher, Agricultural Economics

About Me

My research interests concentrate on time series econometrics and price transmission analysis with a focus on agricultural markets.

I have been really interested in economics since school. After graduating from school, I entered Voronezh State Agrarian University (VSAU), Faculty of Economics. It was not a random choice. Firstly, I live in the Central-Black Earth Region of Russia. It historically formed as an agrarian one, thanks to its exceptionally favorable and unique soil conditions known all over the world. Secondly, The VSAU economic faculty is the oldest of all economic faculties in Voronezh and the largest training and scientific center of education and research in the Central-Black Earth Region in Russia.

Driving licence –



Hobbies -

- Football (soccer)
- Fishing
- Travelling
- History

Awards

2016 – 2017	National Scholarship programme of Slovak Republic SAIA	
	Mobility grant: Slovakia, Nitra, Slovak University of Agriculture in	
	Nitra research 6-month stay)	

2016 – 2016 DAAD scholarship

Mobility grant within DAAD programme: Germany, Kiel, Kiel University (CAU) | research 2-month stay

2014 – 2015 IAMONET-RU Erasmus Mundus Action 2
Mobility grant within European Community Programme: Sweden,
Uppsala, Swedish University of Agricultural Studies | research 6-

2013 – 2014 AURORA Erasmus Mundus Action 2
Mobility grant within European Community Programme: Estonia,
Tartu, University of Tartu | research 2-month stay

Notable publications

month stay

2023 Price transmission between maize and poultry product markets in the Visegrád Group countries: What is more nonlinear, egg or chicken?

Kharin S., Kapustova Z., Lichner I.

Agricultural Economics, Vol. 69, No.12

The Root Collar Diameter Growth Reveals a Strong Relationship with the Height Growth of Juvenile Scots Pine Trees from Seeds Differentiated by Spectrometric Feature

Novikova T., Tylek P., Clíssia Barboza Mastrangelo, Drapalyuk M., Kharin S., Novikov A.

Forests, Vol. 14, No.1164|

2023 Spatial Price Transmission Between Pigmeat Markets in Visegrad

Countries: A Generalized Additive Modelling Approach

Kharin S.

Working Paper IER SAS, Vol. 113, ISSN 1337-5598

2021 Asymmetry in Price Transmission: Evidence from the Wheat-Flour

Supply Chain in Russia

Kharin S.

AGRIS on-line Papers in Economics and Informatics, Vol. 13, No. 3,

pp. 67-75.

2021 Price transmission on agricultural markets: methodological ap-

proaches review (in Russ.)

Kharin S.

Agricultural Science Euro-North-East, Vol. 22(1), pp. 7-20.

2019 Horizontal Price Transmission on the Russian Dairy Market: Non-

linear Approach

Kharin S.

AGRIS on-line Papers in Economics and Informatics, Vol. 11, No. 3,

pp. 45-54.

2018 Price Transmission Analysis: the Case of Milk Products in Russia

Kharin S.

AGRIS on-line Papers in Economics and Informatics, Vol. 10, No. 1,

pp. 15-23.

2017 Price transmission on the Slovak dairy market

Kharin S., Lajdova Z., Beilik P.

Studies in Agricultural Economics, Vol. 119(3), pp. 148-155.

2015 Vertical price transmission along the diary supply chain in Russia

Kharin S.

Studies in Agricultural Economics, Vol. 117(2), pp. 80-85.